Preliminary Inventory of the Jan Kowalik papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Miscellaneous (Box 70)
  Bibliographies and information on various journalists and writers; correspondence and hand illustrated pamphlets of a German poem (circa 1947); correspondence and printed matter from the Carnegie Institute; cards and correspondence from Kali and Henryk (includes photographs of Kali’s paintings); and a list of gift books from the California State Library.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter (Box 71)
  Notebooks on bibliographies from 1942; poems; various journals and notebooks with notes and sketches of buildings and shingles; bibliographies; writings; and correspondence.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1942-1992 (Box 72)
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1942-1983 (Box 73)
- Correspondence, writings, printed matter, and photographs, circa 1980 (Box 74)
- Miscellaneous, 1938-1983 (Box 75)
  Includes a scrapbook of Wanda Black, copies of Polish cartoons collected by Kowalik, writings, pamphlets, and printed matter.
- Sound recordings, circa 1972 (Box 76)
  Compact sound cassettes.
- Writings and printed matter, 1970-1980 (Box 77)
- Card catalog (Boxes 78-81)
  Index cards regarding publications, organized by geographic area and/or subject.
- Card catalog (Boxes 82-86)
  Large index cards on publications, organized by geographic area and/or subject.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1950-1970 (Box 87)
  Includes Tower Talks issues (1952); court case proceedings; Stanford Daily issues (1950s); a file on the Hoover Institution, including newspapers, conference information, and a catalog of selected Hoover microfilm from 1971; and a copy of a Mazowsze book of songs.
- Printed matter, 1940-1950 (Box 88)
  Includes German pamphlets and publications on art and sculpture, postcards, and photographs of Käthe Kollwitz's art.
- Printed matter, circa 1950 (Box 89)
  Material regarding periodicals published outside of Poland.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1922-1954 (Box 90)
  Polish and German publications regarding language and history, bibliographies regarding Mickiewicz in Germany, correspondence, and writings.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1977 (Box 91)
  Three notebooks (one blank) with writings, articles, writings, correspondence, invitations, and newsletters.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1945-1984 (Box 92)
  Writings from the Polish Institute in Beirut, correspondence, bulletins, articles, clippings, pamphlets, and newsletters.
- Writings and printed matter, 1879-1966 (Box 93)
- Printed matter, 1978-1986 (Box 94)
  Includes bulletins of the Polish Arts and Cultural Foundation.
- Printed matter, circa 1980 (Box 95)
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1960-1980 (Box 96)
- Miscellaneous, 1942-1975 (Box 97)
  Large negatives/transparency, Mackiewicz correspondence, and writings.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1975 (Box 98)
  Includes issues of Migrant Echo publication.
- Correspondence and writings, 1948-1955 (Box 99)